{
  "1": {
    "question": "Which one among the following has the largest share of exports from India?\n(a) Agriculture and Allied Commodity\n(b) Gems and Jewellery\n(c) Handicrafts\n(d) Electronic Goods\n",
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "India is the leading diamond exporter in the world with an 18.8% market share of an annual export market worth 127 billion dollars.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "2": {
    "question": "What does GST stand for?\n(a) Goods and Sales Tax\n(b) Government Sales Tax\n(c) Goods and Services Tax\n(d) General Sales Tax\n",
    "answer": "c",
    "more_info": "The goods and services tax (GST) is a value-added tax levied on most goods and services sold for domestic consumption. The GST is paid by consumers, but it is remitted to the government by the businesses selling the goods and services. In effect, GST is indirect tax provides revenue for the government. In India it is a comprehensive, multi-stage, destination-based tax that is levied on every value addition.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "3": {
    "question": "In India, GST became active from which date?\n(a) 1st April, 2017\n(b) 1st January, 2017\n(c) 1st July, 2017\n(d) 1st March, 2017\n",
    "answer": "c",
    "more_info": "The Goods and Service Tax Act was passed in the Parliament on 29th March 2017. The Act came into effect on 1st July 2017. It is an Indirect Tax which has replaced many Indirect Taxes in India.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "4": {
    "question": "Indian GST model has a ____ rate structure.\n(a) 3\n(b) 4\n(c) 5\n(d) 6\n",
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "In India GST model has 4 basic rate structure. They are 5%, 12%, 18% and 28%",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "5": {
    "question": "How many types of taxes are there in Indian GST?\n(a) 2\n(b) 3\n(c) 4\n(d) 5\n",
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "There are three types of taxes :\n1. State GST (SGST)/Union Territory GST (UTGST),\n2. Central GST (CGST) and\n3. Integrated GST (IGST) ",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "6": {
    "question": "Deferred shares can be issued by ______.\n(a) Public Company\n(b) Private Company\n(c) Private company which is deemed to be a Public\n(d) Government Company\n",
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "According to Companies Act 1956, no public limited company or which is a subsidiary of a public company can issue deferred shares",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "7": {
    "question": "A bearer of a share warrant of a comany is _____.\n(a) a creditor of the company\n(b) a member of the company\n(c) a member subject to to certain conditions\n(d) not a member of the company\n",
    "answer": "d",
    "more_info": "A bearer of a share warrant of a company is not a member of the company. But if the articles of association of the company provide it, then the bearer is deemed to be the member of the company. ",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "8": {
    "question": "Which of the following are components of organized sector of stock exchange.\n(a) Commercial bank\n(b) Investors in securities\n(c) Financial institutions like LFC, IDBI\n(d) Other financial institutions\n",
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "Investors in securities are components of organized sector of stock exchange. The organised sector of the capital market comprises all the term-lending financial institutions (or development banks or non-banking financial institutions, like 1DB1, ICICI, etc.), banks with their medium-term and their merchant banking divisions or subsidiaries, LIC, GIC, UTI and the stock exchanges (an essential component of the capital market).",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "9": {
    "question": "Which of the following methods is not used for raising capital through the sale of new securities?\n(a) By issue of prospectus\n(b) Rights issue\n(c) Stock exchange placing\n(d) Private placing\n",
    "answer": "c",
    "more_info": "Stock exchange placing methods is not used for raising capital through the sale of new securities. The companies raise money in the primary market through securities such as shares, debentures, loans and deposits, preference shares etc. Let us take a look the various methods of how new securities are floated in the primary market.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "10": {
    "question": "The first stock exchange was set up in Indian in _____.\n(a) Calcutta\n(b) Bombay\n(c) New Delhi\n(d) Chennai\n",
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "The first stock exchange was set up in India in Bombay. The Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) is the first and largest securities market in India and was established in 1875 as the Native Share and Stock Brokers' Association. ",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "11": {
    "question": "Stock Exchanges in India are under control of ______.\n(a) SEBI\n(b) SEC\n(c) RBI\n(d) financial Institution\n",
    "answer": "a",
    "more_info": "The stock market in each country now is governed/controlled by the corresponding governing bodies in that country. Ex: SEC (Securities Exchange Commission) for USA , SEBI (Securities & Exchanges Board of India) for India. Earlier Stock Exchanges in India were continued to be regulated directly by the Government of India. In the year 1988 the Government of India constituted SEBI to act as the independent regulator of Stock exchanges, the primary market, Mutual Funds etc.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "12": {
    "question": "When a right to sell a security is acquired, it is known as ______.\n(a) call option\n(b) pull option\n(c) double option\n(d) single option\n",
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "When a right to sell a security is acquired, it is known as put option. In finance, a put or put option is a stock market device which gives the owner the right, but not the obligation, to sell an asset (the underlying), at a specified price (the strike), by a predetermined date (the expiry or maturity) to a given party (the seller of the put).",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "13": {
    "question": "When SEBI came into force?\n(a) 1992\n(b) 1991\n(c) 1990\n(d) 1993\n",
    "answer": "a",
    "more_info": "SEBI came into force in 1992. Securities and exchange Board of India (SEBI) was first established in the year 1988 as a non-statutory body for regulating the securities market. It became an autonomous body by The Government of India on 12 May 1992 and given statutory powers in 1992 with SEBI Act 1992 being passed by the Indian Parliament. ",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "14": {
    "question": "What is called to buying of shares by taking money from the broker?\n(a) Margin Trading\n(b) Curb dealing\n(c) Badla\n(d) Forward\n",
    "answer": "a",
    "more_info": "Margin trading is called to buying of shares by taking money from brokers. Buying on margin means to borrow money from a broker (similar to a loan) to purchase stock. The investor can take position in the market by paying an initial margin of 50 per cent (your own money), while the broker could finance the balance 50 per cent. ",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "15": {
    "question": "Indexing is an important ______.\n(a) method of filing\n(b) method of maintaining account books\n(c) aid to filing\n(d) method of maintaining statistical books\n",
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "Indexing is an important method of maintaining account books. Indexes are used to quickly locate data without having to search every row in a database table every time a database table is accessed. ",
    "user_response": "None"
  }
}

